[{"Question":"What is the smallest unit of an element that retains its chemical properties?","option 1":"Molecule ","option 2":"Atom","option 3":"Compound ","option 4":"Ion","answer":"Ion"},{"Question":"In which year did the Government of India set up the first mutual fund by an Act of Parliament?","option 1":"1979","option 2":"1982","option 3":"1963","option 4":"1971","answer":"1963"},{"Question":"Which of the following is considered a capital expense?","option 1":"Â Pension","option 2":"Payment of salaries","option 3":"Â Subsidies","option 4":"Construction of school buildings","answer":"Construction of school buildings"},{"Question":"Which of the following events make us anxious and afraid?","option 1":"Fire","option 2":"Flood","option 3":"All of the above","option 4":"Lightning","answer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Why do events make us anxious and afraid?","option 1":"Events are unpredictable","option 2":"Cause of economic loss and grief","option 3":"It causes adrenaline rush in our body.","option 4":"Only a and b","answer":"Only a and b"},{"Question":"Which of these gave the idea of proper formation of insurance?","option 1":"Babylonian and Chinese Traders","option 2":"Traders from Bharuch and Surat","option 3":"Greeks","option 4":"All of the above","answer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"The â€¦â€¦â€¦â€¦â€¦â€¦â€¦â€¦.. had agreements where they would pay additional sums to lender, as a price for writing off loans, In case a shipment was lost or stolen.","option 1":"Traders from Bharuch and Surat","option 2":"Greeks","option 3":"Chinese Traders","option 4":"Babylonian Traders","answer":"Babylonian Traders"},{"Question":"Which of the following has helped India down the ages as best form of Life Insurance?","option 1":"Nuclear family system","option 2":"Life Insurance penetration","option 3":"Joint family system","option 4":"None of the above","answer":"Joint family system"},{"Question":"\"In India, which of the following statements about the National Investment Fund is true?  \nStatements: \n I. It was created in 2005. \n II. 75% of its annual income was to be used for schemes promoting health, education and employment.  \nIII. It was dissolved in 2018.\"","option 1":"Only statement I","option 2":"Only statement II","option 3":"Â Only statements I and III","option 4":"Â Only statements I and II","answer":"Â Only statements I and II"},{"Question":"Who is known as the father of Blue Revolution in India?","option 1":"Verghese Kurien","option 2":"Sam Pitroda","option 3":"Hiralal Chaudhuri","option 4":"M.S. Swaminathan","answer":"Hiralal Chaudhuri"},{"Question":" Amartya Sen was awarded the Noble Prize for his contribution toâ€“","option 1":"Monetary Economics","option 2":"Welfare Economics","option 3":" Econometrics","option 4":"Development Economics","answer":"Welfare Economics"},{"Question":"Arthashastra by â€œKautilyaâ€ is related withâ€“","option 1":"Military Phase","option 2":"Political Reign","option 3":"Social Phase","option 4":"Economic Postulates","answer":"Political Reign"},{"Question":"Where can we see the values of Indian democracy in the constitution?Â ","option 1":"Preamble","option 2":" Part-3","option 3":" Part-4","option 4":"Part-1","answer":"Preamble"},{"Question":"In which year, the name of Laccadive, Minicoy and Aminidivi Islands was changed in Lakshadweep by parliamentary act-Â ","option 1":"1973","option 2":"1971","option 3":"1970","option 4":"1972","answer":"1973"},{"Question":"How many states are in Union of India-Â ","option 1":"28","option 2":"27","option 3":"30","option 4":"29","answer":"29"},{"Question":"The number of union territories in India are-Â ","option 1":"5","option 2":"7","option 3":"9","option 4":"6","answer":"7"},{"Question":"Under Article 1 of the Indian constitution,it is declared that â€œBharat means India shall be______â€-Â ","option 1":"Union of States","option 2":" Federal State of Unitary features","option 3":" Federal State of Federal features","option 4":"Federal state","answer":"Union of States"},{"Question":"How India is defined article 1 of the constitution-","option 1":" Federal","option 2":"Federal with strong unitary base","option 3":"Confederation","option 4":"Union of states","answer":"Union of states"},{"Question":"The division of power and Independence of judiciary are two important features of â€“Â ","option 1":" Democratic character of government","option 2":"Federal character of government","option 3":"Socialist character of government","option 4":"Unitary character of government","answer":"Federal character of government"},{"Question":"In which of the form, composit India has been described in the constitution-Â ","option 1":"A Union State","option 2":"Semi-Federal","option 3":"Federation of States and Territories","option 4":"Partly Unitary and Partly Federal","answer":"Federation of States and Territories"}]